portfo.li 2010-12-18

# privacy policy

Your privacy is critically important to us. At Portfo.li we have a few fundamental principles:

  * We don’t ask you for personal information unless we truly need it. (We can’t stand services that ask you for things like your gender or income level for no apparent reason.)
  * We don’t share your personal information with anyone except to comply with the law, develop our products, or protect our rights.
  * We don’t store personal information on our servers unless required for the on-going operation of one of our services.

Below is our privacy policy which incorporates these goals:[](http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/2.5/) (Note, we’ve decided to make this privacy policy available under a **Creative Commons Sharealike** license, which means you’re more than welcome to steal it and repurpose it for your own use, just make sure to replace references to us with ones to you, and if you want we’d appreciate a link to portfo.li somewhere on your site. We spent a lot of money and time on the below, and other people shouldn’t need to do the same.) (In fact, this privacy policy was originally created by [Wordpress.com](http://wordpress.com/), thanks guys.)

It is Portfo.li’s policy to respect your privacy regarding any information we may collect while operating our website.

### Website Visitors

Like most website operators, Portfo.li collects non-personally-identifying information of the sort that web browsers and servers typically make available, such as the browser type, language preference, referring site, and the date and time of each visitor request. Portfo.li’s purpose in collecting non-personally identifying information is to better understand how Portfo.li’s visitors use its website. From time to time, Portfo.li may release non-personally-identifying information in the aggregate, e.g., by publishing a report on trends in the usage of its website.

Portfo.li also collects potentially personally-identifying information like Internet Protocol (IP) addresses. Portfo.li does not use such information to identify its visitors, however, and does not disclose such information, other than under the same circumstances that it uses and discloses personally-identifying information, as described below.

### Gathering of Personally-Identifying Information

Certain visitors to Portfo.li’s website choose to interact with Portfo.li in ways that require Portfo.li to gather personally-identifying information. The amount and type of information that Portfo.li gathers depends on the nature of the interaction. For example, we ask visitors who sign up for a portfoli at [Portfo.li](http://portfo.li/) to provide a username and email address. In this case, Portfo.li collects such information only insofar as is necessary or appropriate to fulfill the purpose of the visitor’s interaction with Portfo.li. Portfo.li does not disclose personally-identifying information other than as described below. And visitors can always refuse to supply personally-identifying information, with the caveat that it may prevent them from engaging in certain website-related activities.

### Aggregated Statistics

Portfo.li may collect statistics about the behavior of visitors to its websites. For instance, Portfo.li may monitor the most popular portfolis on the Portfo.li site. Portfo.li may display this information publicly or provide it to others. However, Portfo.li does not disclose personally-identifying information other than as described below.

### Protection of Certain Personally-Identifying Information

Portfo.li discloses potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information only to those of its employees, contractors and affiliated organizations that (i) need to know that information in order to process it on Portfo.li’s behalf or to provide services available at Portfo.li’s websites, and (ii) that have agreed not to disclose it to others. Some of those employees, contractors and affiliated organizations may be located outside of your home country; by using Portfo.li’s websites, you consent to the transfer of such information to them. Portfo.li will not rent or sell potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information to anyone. Other than to its employees, contractors and affiliated organizations, as described above, Portfo.li discloses potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information only when required to do so by law, or when Portfo.li believes in good faith that disclosure is reasonably necessary to protect the property or rights of Portfo.li, third parties or the public at large. If you are a registered user of a Portfo.li and have supplied your email address, Portfo.li may occasionally send you an email to tell you about new features, solicit your feedback, or just keep you up to date with what’s going on with Portfo.li and our products. If you send us a request (for example via a support email or via one of our feedback mechanisms), we reserve the right to publish it in order to help us clarify or respond to your request or to help us support other users. Portfo.li takes all measures reasonably necessary to protect against the unauthorized access, use, alteration or destruction of potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information.

### Cookies

A cookie is a string of information that a website stores on a visitor’s computer, and that the visitor’s browser provides to the website each time the visitor returns. Portfo.li uses cookies to help Portfo.li identify and track visitors, their usage of Portfo.li website, and their website access preferences. Portfo.li visitors who do not wish to have cookies placed on their computers should set their browsers to refuse cookies before using Portfo.li’s websites, with the drawback that certain features of Portfo.li’s websites may not function properly without the aid of cookies.

### Ads

Ads appearing on any of our websites may be delivered to users by advertising partners, who may set cookies. These cookies allow the ad server to recognize your computer each time they send you an online advertisement to compile information about you or others who use your computer. This information allows ad networks to, among other things, deliver targeted advertisements that they believe will be of most interest to you. This Privacy Policy covers the use of cookies by Portfo.li and does not cover the use of cookies by any advertisers.

### Privacy Policy Changes

Although most changes are likely to be minor, Portfo.li may change its Privacy Policy from time to time, and in Portfo.li’s sole discretion. Portfo.li encourages visitors to frequently check this page for any changes to its Privacy Policy. If you have a Portfo.li account, you should also check your portfo.li’s dashboard for alerts to these changes. Your continued use of this site after any change in this Privacy Policy will constitute your acceptance of such change.

If you have questions about accessing or correcting your personal data please contact our [support team](mailto:support@portfo.li).
